[{
  "question": "The Transition Altitude is:",
  "a": "3,000ft",
  "b": "calculated by the Pilot-In-Command",
  "c": "6,000ft",
  "d": "published in the AIP (Section D)",
  "correct": "d"

}, {
  "question": "A person on the ground is struck and seriously injured by a component which has fallen from an aircraft in flight, but the aircraft's flight is not impaired, how would ICAO define the occurrence?",
  "a": "an aircraft incident",
  "b": "In sagittis dui vel nisl. Duis ac nibh. Fusce lacus purus, aliquet at, feugiat non, pretium quis, lectus.",
  "c": "ddubois1@wix.com",
  "d": "Phasellus sit amet erat. Nulla tempus. Vivamus in felis eu sapien cursus vestibulum.",
  "correct": "d"
},{
  "question": "When following a line feature in flight you should keep:",
  "a": "any side as long as the feature is in sight",
  "b": "to the right of that feature",
  "c": "over the top of the feature",
  "d": "to the left of the feature",
  "correct": "b"
},{
  "question": "What kind of light is an Aerodrome Identification Beacon at a civil land aerodrome?",
  "a": "red in colour with identification given by morse code",
  "b": "alternating white/green flashing signal",
  "c": "white in colour with identification given by morse code",
  "d": "green in colour with identification given by morse code",
  "correct": "d"
},{
  "question": "How long is a single engine piston class rating valid for?",
  "a": "10 years",
  "b": "5 years",
  "c": "2 years",
  "d": "1 year",
  "correct": "c"
},{
  "question": "What is the best definition for The Transition Level:",
  "a": "the lowest flight level available for use above the transition altitude",
  "b": "a level calculated and declared for an approach by the Pilot-in-Command",
  "c": "a level published for the aerodrome in the ENR section of the AIP",
  "d": "the highest available flight level below the transition altitude that has been established",
  "correct": "a"
},{
  "question": "ICAO recommend that the colour used for runway markings should be:",
  "a": "orange",
  "b": "white",
  "c": "yellow",
  "d": "yellow or white",
  "correct": "b"
},{
  "question": "At night while flying level, you see the red navigation light of another aircraft at a similar height on a steady relative bearing of 030Â°. What is the situation and what should you do?",
  "a": "there is a collision risk; you should change height to avoid a collision",
  "b": "there is a collision risk; you should turn right",
  "c": "there is a collision risk; no need to take avoiding action as you have right of way",
  "d": "there is no collision risk; no action required",
  "correct": "b"
},{
  "question": "What features should a low intensity obstacle light have on vehicles, other than emergency or security vehicles?",
  "a": "flashing red",
  "b": "fixed yellow",
  "c": "flashing yellow",
  "d": "flashing blue",
  "correct": "c"
},{
  "question": "What additional information is sent when Mode C is selected on the aircraft SSR Transponder?",
  "a": "Altitude based on regional QNH",
  "b": "Height based on QFE",
  "c": "Pressure altitude based on 1013.25hPa",
  "d": "Aircraft height based on subscale setting",
  "correct": "c"
},{
  "question": "At an aerodrome where take-offs and landings are not confined to a runway, the pilot of an aeroplane about to take off shall position and manoeuvre in such a way as to leave clear ..... any aircraft which is taking off:",
  "a": "on the pilot's right",
  "b": "on the pilot's left if the circuit is right hand and on the right if it is left hand",
  "c": "on the pilot's right if the circuit is right hand and on the left if it is left hand",
  "d": "on the pilot's left",
  "correct": "d"
},{
  "question": "Under the rules for avoiding aerial collisions when aircraft are converging:",
  "a": "aeroplanes give way to helicopters and other aeroplanes towing gliders",
  "b": "aeroplanes give way to helicopters and airships",
  "c": "helicopters always give way to aeroplanes",
  "d": "aeroplanes and helicopters give way to aeroplanes towing gliders",
  "correct": "d"
},{
  "question": "Where are approved limitations within which the aircraft is considered airworthy stated?",
  "a": "ICAO Airworthiness Technical Manual",
  "b": "the flight manual and placards in the cockpit",
  "c": "manufacturer's handbook",
  "d": "aircraft maintenance manual",
  "correct": "b"
},{
  "question": "In which part of the AIP can a list with location indicators be found?",
  "a": "AD",
  "b": "LOG",
  "c": "GEN",
  "d": "ENR",
  "correct": "c"
},{
  "question": "If you have a radio communications failure you should squawk:",
  "a": "7500",
  "b": "7600",
  "c": "7000",
  "d": "7700",
  "correct": "b"
},{
  "question": "An airfield with a runway length greater than 1850m has an ATZ height of:",
  "a": "2000ft",
  "b": "2000m",
  "c": "2500m",
  "d": "1000ft",
  "correct": "a"
},{
  "question": "Which of the following is an uncontrolled airspace in the UK?",
  "a": "D",
  "b": "E",
  "c": "A",
  "d": "G",
  "correct": "d"
},{
  "question": "If 'X's are seen before a runway threshold this means:",
  "a": "a displaced threshold, the area of the crosses is unfit for any movement of aircraft",
  "b": "the runway is closed",
  "c": "the runway may be used with caution",
  "d": "a displaced threshold, The area with the arrows cannot be used for landing but is suitable to be used for the take off run",
  "correct": "a"
},{
  "question": "What is the EASA regulation minimum age requirement for a student pilot to fly solo?",
  "a": "18",
  "b": "17",
  "c": "21",
  "d": "16",
  "correct": "d"
},{
  "question": "In the air you are approaching an aircraft head on:",
  "a": "one aircraft should climb and the other descend",
  "b": "the faster aircraft should turn left",
  "c": "both aircraft turn to the right",
  "d": "both aircraft should turn left",
  "correct": "c"
},{
  "question": "When taxiing on the manoeuvring area of an aerodrome a pilot wishes to overtake another aircraft, they must alter course:",
  "a": "as agreed between both pilots of the two aircraft",
  "b": "in accordance with Air Traffic Control instructions",
  "c": "to the right",
  "d": "to the left",
  "correct": "d"
},{
  "question": "The marking with an airfields 'signal square' to indicate a right hand circuit is in force:",
  "a": "a red and yellow striped arrow pointing to the right",
  "b": "a red square overlaid with a diagonal yellow stripe",
  "c": "no signal, circuits are always right hand",
  "d": "a white dumbbell",
  "correct": "a"
},{
  "question": "The secondary surveillance Radar (SSR) transponder code of 7500 is used to indicate:",
  "a": "an emergency/ distress",
  "b": "the VFR (No Suggestions) code",
  "c": "Radio communication failure",
  "d": "unlawful interference",
  "correct": "d"
},{
  "question": "An aircraft must be flown no closer to any vehicle, vessel, person or structure than:",
  "a": "500m",
  "b": "500ft",
  "c": "100ft",
  "d": "1000ft",
  "correct": "b"
},{
  "question": "In Class D airspace, to remain within VMC minima below 3000ft AMSL when flying below 140kts IAS, the minimum flight visibility is:",
  "a": "5km",
  "b": "3km",
  "c": "7km",
  "d": "1.5km",
  "correct": "a"
},{
  "question": "When hiring an aircraft, who is responsible for ensuring that the aircraft is in every way fit and that all maintenance paperwork is valid?",
  "a": "the organisation letting the aircraft",
  "b": "the aircraft commander",
  "c": "the aircraft owner",
  "d": "the approved maintenance organisation",
  "correct": "b"
},{
  "question": "The secondary surveillance Radar (SSR) transponder code of 7000 is used to indicate:",
  "a": "radio communication failure",
  "b": "an emergency / distress",
  "c": "the VFR conspicuity code",
  "d": "unlawful interference",
  "correct": "c"
},{
  "question": "The marking with an airfields 'signal square' to indicate landing is prohibited:",
  "a": "a red 'L' over a white dumbbell",
  "b": "a red square with a diagonal yellow stripe",
  "c": "a red cross on a white background",
  "d": "a yellow cross on top of a red square",
  "correct": "d"
},{
  "question": "The Red and green navigation lights used by a flying machine at night can be seen through:",
  "a": "70 degrees",
  "b": "110 degrees",
  "c": "50 degrees",
  "d": "90 degrees",
  "correct": "b"
},{
  "question": "A runway's Take Off Distance Available (TODA) is defined as:",
  "a": "TORA + Clearway",
  "b": "EDA",
  "c": "EDA + Clearway",
  "d": "TORA + Stopway",
  "correct": "a"
}
]